welcome back to AP US History in under 3
minutes no time for intros let's get
into it so the stage is set Britain has
levied many taxes on the colonies and
the colonists inspired by Enlightenment
thought are reasonably mad in response
to the Intolerable Acts of 1774 the
colonist convened at the First
Continental Congress to try and solve
the issue however then militia men
engage with British troops in the town
of Lexington and once those British
troops March to the town of Concord even
more militia men fired upon them forcing
them to retreat under constant Guerilla
style attacks on their March back to
Boston the revolution had begun and
understand that the colonies didn't have
an organized Army at the Second
Continental Congress colonists attempted
to fix this by a stablishing the
Continental Army however this Army
headed by George Washington was filled
with militia men who had no formal
military training England had been
established for thousands of years and
had an organized military and financial
advantages because of this the first
part of this revolution saw the British
winning most every battle Bunker Hill
Quebec Long Island Fort Washington all
these battles saw the British winning
but showed the colonists could put up a
fight this especially is shown in the
Battle of Trenton where Washington's
surprise attack after crossing the
Delaware River Saw the colonist win it
was also around this time that Thomas
Payne published Common Sense and later
America would declare their independence
the fact is throughout all these early
engagements colonist morale was boosted
and forces kept growing in the colonies
which caused colonists to win more
battles this all culminated in the
turning point of the Revolution being
the Saratoga campaign throughout the
entire early part of this revolution
leaders like Ben Franklin had tried to
get the French To Join the Revolution on
the colonist side when the colonies won
the Battle of Saratoga this finally
convinced the French To Join the
Revolution now we start seeing the
colonists along with the now French
victories in this revolution Stony Point
Newton King's Mountain Chesapeake all
leading to one decisive battle in the
town of Yorktown where rough fighting
for over 3 weeks with a joint American
and French siege that trapped the
British caused the colonist to win and
finally in 1783 with the signing of the
Treaty of Paris the Revolution was over
with the British finally recognizing
America's Independence and anyone can
argue the true reason America won
however looking at the troop numbers
from the beginning of this revolution to
the end the one thing to take away is
that it was the colonist ideological
commitment resilience and assistance
sent by European allies that truly
caused America to come out on top on the
screen now are questions for this topic
pause
now I'll put the answers on the screen
no see you in the next one